back and today we are going to start
with new and very important topic in
Kafka that is a schema registry.
And again, I'll tell you that till now
what we have a covered is setting up a
setting up producer, consumer, cluster,
idempotency, transaction.
So, this is a schema registry is one of
the topic where if you want to know if
engineer has actually worked with Kafka
or not.
Because
like in production you will see that the
schema registry is something very
frequently used.
If you are not using a schema registry,
I will tell you what's the problem are.
Okay.
So,
till now what we have done is let's say
producer.
This is the payload which it want to
publish.
This is the message.
Okay. We have order ID, customer ID,
quantity, total amount.
First,
it will goes to serializer.
Serializer will convert it to bytes. And
after you we have I've already covered
into a producer that after serializer
there are many steps like partition and
all.
So, after those step once the JSON
serializer converted into byte,
ultimately that goes to the Kafka.
Now from Kafka when consumer
fetch the record, fetch the data,
ultimately it goes to a deserialization
step.
And in the deserialization step, it will
again convert it back to an object.
So, this is what we have seen till now.
But in production, this will not work.
Why is so?
See, I'll tell you five
use cases
where this scenario will break in
production.
Use case one.
Addition of new field. So, see this use
case. So, now let's say producer has
increased to version two of order
and has added a new field shipping
address.
Whereas consumer is still on the older
version.
So you might say that hey
both producer and consumer is reading
the same
let's say some repo
which host order. But it's still they
can have different version because let's
say if producer make a change
added a shipping address
into this order then it can increase the
version and it also
increase the version of this repo.
But it's still the consumer is still on
the version one of this repo which has
the order which doesn't have
shipping address.
Okay? So this is a very
genuine and possible scenario.
So producer is on version two of order
where a new field has been added whereas
consumer is still on version one of
order where this field is missing.
So what would happen?
So in the JSON serializer the it will be
converted into bytes published to Kafka
from JSON deserializer what would happen
is
Jackson might ignore this unknown field
because see shipping address now it has
to map to this
consumer order since
there is no
similar field it might get ignored.
But if you have
set up in a strict mode in the Jackson
like this
let's say this is your Jackson you are
doing a JSON deserializer in that if you
have put a strict mode fail on unknown
properties then this will also throw an
exception.
So this is one use case.
Another use case is removal of existing
field.
So again producer has moved to the
version two of order in which it has
removed this total amount field.
But, consumer is still on the version
one of the order where this field is
still accepted.
expecting. Okay? So, what would happen?
So, when the consumer read the record
and go through the deserialization
phase, so Jackson
assign for the primitive type, it will
assign default value, for object, null.
And this is very, very risky.
Why? Because, see,
producer is not even sending the total
amount.
Total amount could be 100, 200, but it
is not sending it.
But, the Jackson has assigned for the
primitive type, it has assigned zero.
Now, your business logic will run
directly on top of it, and you will
think that, "Hey, okay, total amount is
zero." And your business logic will run.
This could lead to a serious bug.
Okay? So, there is no validation at all
whether
this field is missing or not, or whether
this is just a default value which has
been added. So, who is validating it? No
one.
So, this is another use case.
Third use case, rename of a field. Let's
say, producer is still on a version two
of order, but it has renamed the field
from total amount to amount.
But, consumer is still on the version
one.
Okay? And it is expecting total amount.
And it is sending it. But, what would
happen is, since consumer is not aware
of it, so there could be a you can say
that a silent loss of data. Producer is
sending amount which has a proper value,
100.
But, consumer doesn't have
a way
to determine that this amount is equals
to this total amount, and this would
lead to a silent loss of data.
It won't be able to map, and this would
be set with a default value.
Fourth, change of field type.
Now, producer has moved to a version two
of order where it has changed quantity
from int
to a string.
Now, and consumer is still on the
version one of order
and it is expecting quantity to be int.
What would happen?
Your JSON deserializer, the Jackson will
throw an exception, JSON mapping
exception.
Use case five, multiple consumer
different expectation.
So, see in real world
one producer can integrate like multiple
consumer. Okay, consumer one
consumer two
consumer three.
So, the consumer one want all fields.
Hey, for order I want all these fields.
Consumer two say that, hey, I only want
order ID and total amount. Consumer
three says that, oh, okay, I only need
order ID and shipping address.
So, different consumer has different
expectation.
So, what if
producer keep on changing its schema
based on the consumer request?
There is no contract between producer
and consumer that, hey, producer will
only provide this.
There is no contract. Currently, it's
simple JSON, raw JSON. So, there is no
validation, no compatibility check.
Producer can change whatever it want.
So, let's say new consumer comes,
consumer four. Hey, I want this new
field to be added. What producer simply
added and return it.
Okay? Now, all the old consumer
started also seeing this. So, there is
no validation how the old consumer will
behave.
What if consumer four says that, hey, I
want this field to be int
integer. Earlier, it was a string. You
simply change it
without doing any validation.
So, that's why when we have deal with
multiple they have different
expectation. This could lead to chaos.
If there is no proper agreement or
contract between producer and consumer.
So, these are the five use cases which
can happen in live if you're working
with the Kafka production.
And this is the real
you can say that pain point of a
developer.
And the solution for this is a schema
registry, very popular and very highly
used in the industry with Kafka.
So, a schema registry. The first thing
we have to understand is what is a
schema?
A schema is nothing but considered as a
definition, formal definition of the
structure of data.
So, it is just a definition that hey,
this is field one,
this would be of this type. This is
field two, this would be of this type.
So, you can say that you're providing
certain definition or you can say that
uh proper contract.
That
for order,
you would find only this field and this
field is of this this type and this is
the order.
Okay?
So, there are many
different you can say that we have Avro,
Protobuf, JSON schema.
But
Avro is the most popular with Kafka.
This is most popular. Protobuf also you
can use it, but this is very frequently
used.
And what is a schema registry? A schema
registry you can say that it maintains
this a schema, its version.
Any change in a schema,
first it also perform a validation,
compatibility check.
So, a schema you understand, it's just a
format.
Okay? It's just a definition.
Field type like this.
A schema registry is maintain this a
schema. Okay, version.
And if any new version comes, it do the
validation that the new version is
compatible with the old one or not.
So, very high level, very high level and
very simple term if I have to explain, a
schema registry brings validation before
producer publish an event.
That's all.
Okay. Now, earlier producer was using
the JSON serializer. Now, it won't use
JSON serializer. It uses appropriate
serializer. If you are using this a
schema,
Avro, you will have Avro serializer.
Protobuf, Protobuf serializer. So,
appropriate serializer we have to use.
And what it will do is
it will check with a schema registry
first. Hey,
I am going to publish an event. I'm
going to do a send. This is the topic.
This is the key. This is the value.
Okay. This is I'm going to publish.
So, this is the schema for this, right?
So, it will just say that, "Hey, I am
going to publish this value
validated." So, a schema registry first
validated
if this a schema
whatever I'm going to publish
if it is compatible
means it will not break consumer. Let's
say, in simple term it will say that it
will not break your consumer.
It will say that, "Yes,
you are good to go."
And then only it will publish to the
Kafka. And this is happened for every
send.
For every send,
whenever you are sending an event to a
Kafka, first a schema registry comes
into the picture.
It validate whatever you are sending,
the message.
It should not break consumer.
If not,
you can go ahead and publish to Kafka.
Otherwise, this a schema registry will
throw an exception.
So, in simple terms, the schema registry
brings validation
before producers send an event. But,
this brings so many question.
Does with every send, are we calling a
schema registry? Will it not making uh
latency impact? Okay? And how this the
flow works actually?
So, for that, we have to go one level
deeper.
So, I'll show you a step-by-step with
demo
and things will get clear.
So, but very high level, all I want to
have at this point of time understanding
is that
every
message you are sending through Kafka,
first validation, it will pass through
validation.
It will check
that consumer would be able to
consumer will get break or not.
How? How it will check? What is the
logic?
Okay? How version is maintained? All
this question
good get ultimately resolved now.
Okay? So, let's go deeper.
So, step one, we have to download the
schema registry and we have to make it
run.
So, there are many providers you can
use. You can use Confluent schema
registry, which is the most popular one.
You can use AWS Glue schema registry,
Azure schema registry, all this you can
use. So, I am going with the Confluent
schema registry, which is very popular
in the industry and many big
product-based companies uses it. Okay?
So, you can run this command. So, 8.2.0
is the latest one. And but, whichever
the version you are interested in, you
can go and download the community
version of it. Okay? So, you can use
this command or directly goes to the
Confluent archive. Whatever the version
you are interested in, you can download
its JAR.
Currently, I am not showing you the
Docker way because I haven't covered
Docker. So that
more doubts will come like how I'm
this Docker is running. So for now, we
are doing manually. We are manually
downloading the jar and making it up.
So this will also make things little
clear.
Docker abstracts a lot of thing. And but
I will soon cover Docker
in the series also. Different series.
So
once we have downloaded it. So let's say
I have downloaded it.
Within that, you will see there is
within this
ETC schema registry, you will see this
schema hyphen registry.properties.
So you have to open it
and
select the port number. Currently,
whichever the port number you want to
make it run.
Just select it. So I have selected 8085
because by default it give with 8081,
but my already broker is running I think
on 8081. So I have used this port number
8085.
The second is that schema registry has
to talk with Kafka.
For what purpose? I will show you. But
it has to talk with Kafka. So that we
have to provide the bootstrap server
like we are providing with our producer.
Producer talk with Kafka, right? And in
the producer, we provide the bootstrap
server. Similarly, consumer talk with
Kafka. And in the consumer also, we have
provided the bootstrap server.
Similarly, schema registry also talk
with Kafka.
So here also, we have to provide the
bootstrap server. So you might be
thinking why it has to talk with Kafka?
I will show you.
So I will provide it my both brokers
which are running.
Okay?
And this topic
underscore schema, which is the default
one it has. You can change it the name.
But this is the default. I would suggest
keep it the same.
So
why it talks to the Kafka? Because it
create
this topic.
Okay? And within this topic itself, it
manages the schema, its version. I'll
show you that one.
But at this point of time,
in step one, we have to download the
schema registry, whichever you are
interested in. I would suggest go with
Confluent.
Whichever the version you wanted.
Once you have downloaded it,
open this schema-registry.properties
with within ETC and a schema registry
folder.
And add your port number, which is free,
and the bootstrap server.
Okay?
And after that, we can start our
controller and broker.
Okay? And also the schema registry. So,
means our Kafka is running, our you can
say that uh
you can producer consumer you can start
later, but let's say our Kafka is
running, both uh broker and controller,
and after that, our schema registry,
which is talking to it.
Okay? And we can test that if it is
running or not. So, let me show you.
Let's do that first.
So, here,
this I have downloaded Confluent 8.2.0,
and within this ETC folder,
schema registry,
we have a schema-registry.properties.
So, here in this one,
we have, let's say, VI
ETC
schema registry.
So, here, I have already set up like uh
the port number 8085, which I wanted,
and the Kafka bootstrap server. Okay?
And no need to change the topic name,
which it will create. Okay? So, you can
add this.
Now, let's uh start. So, before starting
the schema registry, we have to start
the controller. So, I've already showed
you how you can start the controller.
So, I'm starting controller one.
Starting controller two.
Okay, so both are started.
I'm started broker one.
I'm starting broker two.
Okay, and after that now I'm starting.
We have to start the schema.
So here, we can run this command.
So let's copy this one. So I'm already
inside this 8.2.0.
Okay, so I'll use this from here.
So also
Yeah, so I'm already inside this
Confluent 8.2.0 folder.
So we are starting this.
Okay, and we can run this command
to see
that it is
running. So it is showing empty means
everything runs.
So our first thing is running. Our first
setup schema registry setup is done. So
our Kafka is up. Both the broker and
controller and schema registry is up.
Cool.
Step two.
So step two is now
producer creates a contract. Okay, so
producer is the one which publish the
message.
Okay, so let's say this is the first
time
producer publishing a message. So
our schema registry which maintains this
topic
_schema. Currently this topic has no
data. It is empty.
So this is the first time I'm telling
you that producer has to create the
contract first time. Producer is sending
the message. So that's why it has to
create the schema.
So what all things required?
Okay. So, first thing
producer
Our producer need to have this
order.avsc
file.
Okay. So, this is you can say that the
schema
definition.
If you are using Protobuf, you might
have Protobuf file order.certain.proto
or something. So, that will be the
Protobuf definition you can give.
Okay?
So,
this .avsc
we can define the schema. So, you can
say that it's a contract between
producer and consumer.
So, now in this avsc format, we can put
type. Type is nothing but consider that
it's an object.
So, whatever the field it is writing,
consider that it's an object. Record
means object.
You can provide the name of this.
Okay. Well, so you can say that this dot
avsc
will be converted to Java object.
Will be converted to Java object.
And when it converted to Java object,
this name is ultimately become the name
of the Java class, order.java.
And this record tells that this is an
object.
Type is record means object.
So, ultimately this class will be
converted to a Java object.
And name is Java object would be
order.java.
And this Java object
order.java
would be created within a namespace
com.edea.schema.
Under this path, it will be get created.
Okay? And these are the field which will
get added in this order object that
string order ID is string consumer ID is
string product ID int quantity double
total amount.
So, these all field will be created.
But, please note that
this object which will get created, this
is not a simple POJO. This is not a
normal POJO that, okay, a class order
would be created and it is just has
field all this field with just getter
and setter. No.
This is you can say that very very
specific for serializer.
Okay. So, it has many additional method
like get the schema which serializer
will use it.
The get the schema will return this
schema itself complete internally.
It also has method which help the
serializer
to serialize the
object, you can say.
So, in simple term
the first step producer has to define
the schema definition. And whatever the
schema you can say that you are using
Avro, Protobuf, JSON schema,
based on that
you can create that one file where you
will specify the definition.
Okay. So, this is
.avsc for Avro in which I have made the
type record name order, name is space
given, and these are the field.
So, dependency we needed. Who will parse
this?
So, we have created this file. But,
somebody need to parse this file, right?
So, we need a dependency first.
So, that's where I have shown the
dependency. This dependency
org.apache.avro
the version, the latest version which we
are using it. This knows how to parse
this schema.avsc.
Okay?
Then also, we have to create an Java
object out of this .avsc. How to do
that?
This plugin we have to add.
Okay? So, what this plugin will do?
Source directory.
So, it will read this file.
So, this file I have kept under
AVRO folder. So, from this
source main AVRO, from this folder
this dot
AVSC file would be readed.
It will generate a Java object and it
will put into this path.
\slash} generated source \slash} AVRO
and the
name is com.eda.schema.
com.eda.schema/order.java.
Okay? So, this plugin is used to create
a Java class out of this AVSC.
And we have one more dependency, which
is
brings the serialization and
deserialization logic. So, this
serializer. So, currently we are using
AVRO, so we need AVRO serializer.
And this serializer also brings the
deserializer logic also.
Now, we will go one level more deep like
what task serializer do.
Okay? And why we need
to convert this AVSC file to Java
object. What's the purpose? I will show
you. But, first thing
we have to understand that producer has
to define the schema because producer is
the one who is publishing the message.
So, who who is the best
to define the schema? Producer.
And
whichever protocol you are using, I am
using AVRO, so this is the way to define
the schema, dot AVSC.
Okay?
Now,
producer is making the first send call
to Kafka.
First send call.
So, first thing we have to do is we have
to do Maven clean compile. Why? Because
when you do Maven clean compile
this plugin will run.
It will convert this dot avsc
to Java
class.
Okay? It will read from this source and
it will create a Java class within this.
So, once that is done, understand the
flow. So, producer is trying to do a
send. Here, this is the topic. This is
the key.
Now, the value is order object which is
generated from dot avsc. Because see,
now we are working with Avro serializer.
It only understand
the value.
Okay? The See, whether we can have key
serializer can do two things. Key
serializer and the value serializer,
correct?
Okay? So, let's say for the simplicity,
I'm saying key is a string normal string
only. Nothing
different. Okay? It's not an object.
It's string only.
For value
I am using and
this one.
Order object, but it is generated from
dot avsc. This order object I have not
written.
So, from this dot avsc, when I did Maven
clean compile, this order object class
is created.
Now, using that
I created an object from that class
and
used as a value.
Now, Avro serializer understand this.
Okay? It understand this that okay
this order object because see how it
understand that? Because when we create
a Java class out of this dot avsc, this
is not a normal pojo. It also extend a
specific record base.
So, you can say that this Avro
understand that, okay,
this is the object which is created
through \dot} AVSC. Now, I have to
serialize it.
So, what is step it will do?
First, it will call it will get the
schema.
I told you that every send we are doing
going to do, it pass through validation.
But, there are a lot of things happen.
Just when we say validation, lot of
things happen. So, now go step by step
and little slow.
So, first time send is happening.
And
the producer has called the send.
Request reach to the serializer. So, we
are using Avro serializer. This
dependency we have added, right? Avro
serializer.
What it will do?
It will see that, okay,
order object
\dot} get a schema.
So, whatever the schema I will get. So,
here
when from \dot} AVSC we get this class,
it is just a non not a normal project.
It has additional method like get a
schema, which return to the complete
schema that field type. This field type
like this.
So, what it will do is it will generate
a hash of this a schema first.
Okay?
So,
your order matters. So, whatever the
field
you are adding into this,
that their order matter also.
Because we are generating an hash of
this a schema.
And this will check, hey,
do I have a schema ID for this a schema
hash?
Currently, we are doing first time, so
definitely no, we don't have anything.
Okay? So, what it will do? It will try
to register the schema because it's a
first time and we don't have a schema ID
for this schema hash. So, it will
register it. So, it will invoke
First time it will make an HTTP call
to a schema registry.
Okay, what info it will pass? It will
pass the subject. Subject is nothing but
topic
hyphen
value or topic hyphen key. So, you know
that serialization works at two places.
Key we can have key serializer, we can
have value serializer.
Okay?
So, for simplicity now
we are for key we are using string
serializer only. Okay, only for value we
are using object but not a simple JSON
uh serializer.
We are using Avro.
Okay, so that's why this flow comes into
the picture.
So,
subject would be topic order hyphen
event hyphen value. So, we are only
currently
doing value. So, only for value we are
using an object which is generated from
\dot} AVSC.
So, the subject would be passed order
hyphen event hyphen value
and
the schema. This is schema, right? The
complete schema for this one. That would
be passed.
Now, a schema registry what it will do?
It will check.
Hey, do I have
this
order hyphen event hyphen value this
subject? So, this is called subject.
Hey, do I already have this subject?
Currently no, this is the first time,
right? So, it is not present. So, what
it will do within a Kafka
it will store this details into this
topic. Underscore schema topic it will
store this.
Subject is order hyphen event hyphen
value, version one because this is the
first time request is coming. The schema
okay? The order schema, right?
So, order ID string, customer ID string,
quantity in
total amount double and the
compatibility backward. That I will
cover later. Why this is also important.
This is default. Since we haven't not
provided anything by default is
backward.
Now what and the schema ID. So it
generate one unique ID for this.
Now what the schema registry will return
it? It will return the schema ID
back to our
Avro serializer.
Okay, now we got the schema ID 1001. So
what it will do? It will put into cache.
So what it will put into uh cache? The
hash schema hash.
So whatever the schema, it will generate
a hash, right? So against that schema
hash, it will put the schema ID.
And once that done,
it will
complete the serialization process. Now
in the serialize, what it will add?
One magic byte,
then a schema ID, and the payload.
So magic byte is nothing. Currently it's
always zero.
Okay? This tell the deserializer what
the version of the wire protocol. With
this, deserializer know how to interpret
rest of the byte.
Okay, so in simple terms if I would say,
when the request goes to the
deserializer, when the deserializer
receive this,
so deserializer say that, okay, zero.
Then it you can say that it's a version
of the protocol
uh for this Avro. It knows that, okay,
for the version zero,
next four byte is a schema ID and after
that payload. Maybe in future when magic
byte comes one, let's say,
then
the deserializer has the value that,
okay, next six bytes I need to run as a
schema ID and after that would there
would be a data.
Okay, so for now zero is uh present.
Currently there is no other version
for this Avro protocol.
So
first it will add a magic byte, which is
currently always zero. Then
it will add the schema ID. Whatever the
schema ID which has been generated.
Okay? It will add that, which is 1001,
right? It will add it into this. So, 4
bytes. And after that, our payload.
And one very important part that within
the payload, if you remember in our
JSON, what goes into the payload?
Our field
and the value.
Let's say order ID
and the
data.
But in the Avro,
the payload only values goes.
Okay? Only values go. So, let's say this
is the magic.
This is the schema. Generally, this is
stored in binary form.
But for only simplicity and learning
purpose,
I just represented in the normal plain
text itself. But generally, it should be
in the binary form.
So, one Here, if you see, I have a magic
bit. Then, 4 byte you have the
schema ID, 1001.
And the payload. Now, within the
payload, I directly have only values. No
field and value. So, first is
order, then consumer ID, then total
quantity then quantity and total amount.
Why not field?
See, we have added the schema ID, right?
From this schema ID,
schema registry has the schema present.
And I told you that order matters. So,
it knows that when I have in the
payload, I have already values.
55.0. It knows that for this schema ID,
the first is order ID, this first is
order ID. Then, customer ID, this is
customer ID. Then, quantity, this is
quantity. Then, total amount, this is
total amount.
So, with this, it
you can say that
it save the memory, also.
Okay? So, there is a lot of
you'll need less of
So, you got it?
What is happening? And ultimately, this
data goes to the Kafka.
So, this flow is clear?
So, now in this application properties,
what we have to add?
So, first thing is this is common in the
producer. We added a bootstrap server.
We added a key serializer. Currently, I
told you that we are using string
serializer only. But, it is also
possible that for key serializer, also
you can have a Kafka Avro serializer.
Okay? But, for that, you need
its file also. Let's say object key.avsc
file. And inside this, whatever the
field you wanted to have
uh put, you can add it. But, if it is a
normal string, you can have a string
serializer.
But, for say here, currently, over only
value
we are using
Kafka Avro serializer. It's an object,
but we are not using plain Java
serializer. We are using Kafka Avro.
So, we are going to create
Okay?
Object.
Which is
compatible with this Avro serializer.
It's It will be not like simple
order.java. No.
It would This class would be created
from dot
avsc file.
Okay? And this is not a normal pojo.
Avro serializer understand this.
So, value serializer is Kafka Avro
serializer.
And this is the schema registry URL
where your schema registry is running.
So, I told you, right? That serializer
need to make a call here
to register the schema.
So, it make a HTTP call. So, it need to
know where your schema is running.
So, HTTP localhost 8085 it is running.
So, in simple you need to tell the
producer where is your schema registry
and also
the value serializer
whatever you are using. So, we are using
Kafka Avro serializer, not simple JSON
serializer.
Only this thing we have to add.
Okay, so let's see that.
First, let's see that.
So, everything is running. Our producer
is running, broker is running, our
schema registry is running. This is our
schema registry is running.
Okay, now we have to make our producer
up and running. So, this is our
producer.
This is order.avsc.
Type is record, name is order. This is
the name space.
Okay, so this is very simple avsc file.
And uh
during application startup, this
topic would be created, order-event.
Okay.
I have an order controller
order controller class.
In that, very simple, what I'm doing is
that whatever the request I am getting,
order ID, customer ID, quantity, total
amount.
So, I am invoking the product service,
send order. Now, here if you see in
this, this order.
I have not created this class.
Okay, this class extend a specific
record base. This is auto generated from
avsc file.
Okay.
So, this I told you, right? This is not
a normal pojo. This also has a builder
capability. So, like in a builder design
pattern way, we can create this object,
order.new builder.
You can set order ID consumer ID,
product ID, quantity, total amount,
bill, whatever you have to set.
Whatever you have to set, set it.
And then ultimately call the send.
KafkaTemplate.send, we have this is the
topic we have to publish. This is the
key.
Now, value if you see the order
order is
this.
Which is Avro generated one.
Correct?
So, only order value is generated from
the Avro base. Key is normal simple
string.
So, that's why in the
application.properties key is normal
string serializer.
But, value I have told go with Avro
serializer. Now, Avro serializer for
value
it knows what it has to do.
Okay?
It will perform all these step. Avro
serializer perform all these step that
okay, whatever the object I'm getting
call the get a schema and this get a
schema will return the data.
Why it will return the data? Because
this this is not a normal POJO. This is
created from dot AVSC file.
This is dot AVSC file, right?
So, this class
this order class
has get a schema method. So, those will
work fine.
Okay?
And after that in pom.xml
you have the Avro serializer dependency
and the schema dependency
and the plugin.
Which will generate the Java class.
Okay? So, in terminal I'm just simply
doing first Maven
clean
compile first.
Okay? So, that
if you see in the target generated
source
Avro
now inside this this is our schema
com.edureka.schema.order.
So, this get created.
After that I'm starting the producer
application
up.
Okay? Producer application is up and
running. Now, we just have to hit this
endpoint.
Which endpoint? /api/avro/orders.
So, /api/avro/orders
we have to hit this endpoint.
This is I am sending.
Okay?
Send.
Order sent to order events.
So,
partition two offset zero. Now, let's
see.
Now, first uh
we have to see
we have to describe the schema first.
So, here let's zoom it a bit.
So, here if you see the topic, a schema
is created.
It has only one partition which has two
replica. That's all.
One partition two replica. So, leader is
three means our broker one is the leader
for this schema.
Similarly, for
order-events
or event, let me see.
So, the message got published to
partition two offset zero. Partition two
is the leader three. Both the broker
one. Broker one is the leader.
So, now let's see the broker one.
So, broker one logs
zoom it a bit.
Broker one logs
partition two.
Okay, so let's
zoom it a bit.
So, this is the data. Okay? So, our
event got successfully published, but in
the form of binary.
Now, also let's see
the schema.
So, a schema
But, I think broker one itself is the
leader, right? For a schema
a schema has only one partition zero.
Which is leader three. Leader three is
our broker one.
So if I check the broker one
and schema is underscore schema hyphen
zero.
No, schemas.
Correct, schemas.
So here if you see this data.
So this holds the schema information.
Order ID type is a string, name type is
customer ID type is a string. Similarly,
product ID type is a string, quantity
type is int, total amount type is
double.
Okay, it has the version also.
So this is the whole schema present, its
version present also.
Got it?
So
this flow is clear? That what happened
when you do the first time send? So I
only did the first time send, right? So
when I did the first time send it
created a hash.
No value present. It will register it.
Currently we are for value only we are
using this Avro base. So this Avro
serializer knows that okay
this value
I have to
find out the schema, generate a hash.
Currently there is no schema present
into the cache, so it will ask the
schema registry register it.
Since it is the first time, there is no
history, it will create. The subject is
your topic hyphen value or key. So
currently we are only for the value uh
we are using Avro serializer, right?
I showed you
that currently in application.property
only for value
we are using Avro serializer.
But for key also if you have to use so
for key also you have to make Kafka Avro
serializer.
Then you have to create one more
like order key.avsc if it's an object,
right? So, you have to create
order key.avsc.
Okay? And within this controller
order ID
then
simple
you won't have to create. Then you have
to have like order key whichever you
will create the class from .avsc. Then
you have to pass that one.
So, then serializer will automatically
know that I have to register that also.
Okay? But they don't uh you can say that
conflict with each other because subject
is different.
Topic is same, but hyphen value hyphen
key.
So, currently for key I am using string
serializer only, no problem. Only for
value I am using Avro serializer.
So, for value only it will try to get
whatever the object I send, get a
schema.
And this will work because this is not a
simple pojo, it is created from .avsc
file, so it has the schema. This method
will pass.
Okay?
Generate a hash. Cache do not have it.
It will register it and ultimately
schema registry put it into a schema
topic. This I have showed you.
It will return this schema ID.
It will put into the cache now.
After that it will serialize.
Magic byte
a schema ID and the payload.
Payload only contain values, not field
name
because with this schema ID it can take
out the schema.
And order men matters, so with each
order it knows the values
also. And ultimately this goes to the
Kafka.
Okay?
Clear?
Now, what happen
when producer make a second call but
after changing the schema. Now, let's
say that what I am saying is
Now,
I am changing
quantity into a string.
Okay? Now, let's say producer has moved
to next version. Some Some consumer
asked me that, "Hey, I want quantity as
a string." And I changed it. I do not
bother that, "Okay, if any consumer read
my old message which was in, will it
break or not?" I don't care. This is a
new request comes, I change it simply
blindly.
Now, what would happen? Now, let's say
that whatever the data would come.
Now, quantity will come in a string.
Let's accept in a string now.
Okay? Uh
this would be become our string.
And our set quantity would be a string.
So, I just need to
Maven clean
compile again, so that from AVSC new it
will create.
Okay?
So, ultimately this should pass.
So, currently it's not updated. So, just
a sec. \dot} AVSC is string.
quantity
So, it has not updated. Uh now, let me
check.
Let us stop the producer first.
And Maven clean compile again.
Close it and
open it again.
It's strange.
Quantity I changed to a string.
Okay, this is a string.
order
This should get changed to
This should get updated.
Clear. Currently, okay. Sorry. Sorry. I
am in different folder.
So, this is the producer folder, right?
So, for producer, we have to do Maven
clean
compile. Now, it will do.
Okay.
Something wrong.
ordercontroller.java
So, just remove it.
Okay. Now, let's do.
Cool.
So, now here if you see, in this order,
this become to the character sequence.
And
this change we have done. That's it.
Earlier, we have published a message
with int. Now, I am trying
to publish. I have changed this
based on the request with the consumer.
I have changed it.
Now, let me start the
producer again.
I started the producer.
I am publishing, but quantity this time
as a string.
What would happen?
Internal server error.
Exception.
What is the exception?
It says that
Here.
Type mismatch.
The type of the field in the new schema
does not match with the old schema.
Okay. A string not compatible with the
writer type int.
So, now what exactly happened?
See, in the validation,
this is failed. What happened?
So, in the order.avsc, now let's say
producer has changed from int to string.
This is what I have done, right?
Correct? I have changed it.
I did Maven clean install, Maven clean
compile. So, it created a new
order.java class, which now this
quantity as a string.
And when I try to publish it,
it throws an exception.
That it does not match with the old
schema.
So, what's the flow exactly? So, now
understand this. Now, when producer try
to do send,
and the value here,
this is the schema, right? Which is now
this order object is again generated
from avsc only. And now this time this
is a string. Correct?
We have changed it. When we do Maven
clean compile, this got changed.
Now this ultimately goes to the
serializer, Avro serializer, and you
know that for value in the
application.properties, for value we are
using Avro serializer. Okay? So, this
will ultimately accept this.
Now it knows that for Avro serializer,
whatever the object I am getting, I need
to do get a schema. It will do It will
get it because from avsc only we
generated this order object. So, we get
the schema. And we generate the hash.
Remember that when the previous time
when we did hash, generate hash, that
time quantity was int.
This time it is a string.
So, hash will not be same, correct?
So,
whatever the hash I will get now, is
this present into cache? No.
It is not present. So, it will try to
register it. It will try to register it.
So, it will pass the subject. Subject is
topic- value.
Like value. So, order- event. So, we are
trying to do value serializer, right?
So, hyphen value.
And the schema it will pass.
Now schema registry will check.
Hey, this is the subject I am getting,
order- event- value.
Do I have it? It will say that yes,
we already have a subject version one is
already present with this is schema
compatibility type is backward.
This is the schema ID.
>> [snorts]
>> So now this will run.
Whether
do some compatibility check and do the
validation whether the new schema which
is getting
will it break
the consumer or not?
Okay.
If it failed, it will throw exception.
If it pass, it will add like 1002 schema
ID, subject version two, and the new
schema whatever whatever get passed and
the compatibility type.
So at this point of time this got
failed. This check got failed.
Okay, since this failed, this request
got failed.
Now you might be asking that how it
determine that this will fail or not.
What's the validation?
So this compatibility check based upon
this backward we have something called
forward
full
There are many. I will do I will show
you in the last once we complete the
whole flow.
Okay. But
remember that a schema registry at this
point of time determine that hey now you
have changed the quantity to string.
But in Kafka there is int present for
this. Old message present
with int type.
If consumer
let's say
which is let's say
on this new schema, for example, a
string.
If it get int
will it break or not break?
So there are different
you can say that validation logic which
depend upon backward and forward and
full. I will
tell you with example at the bottom of
this.
But at this point of time, don't worry
about this like how it determine whether
this should whether this need to be
failed or not.
This is schema need to be failed or not.
This is not a concern at this point of
time because I will cover it soon.
At this point of time, what I wanted you
to understand that
every time now producer is sending.
So this is schema producer might have
changed.
So it doesn't directly goes to Kafka. It
first goes to this flow.
The schema registry run the validation.
Now the new schema which you are going
to publish
is it compatible
or not? Is it compatible change?
Backward compatible or not?
If not,
throw exception like it is throwing
here.
What are the rules? I will tell you
soon. But this flow is clear, right?
Avro serializer where it comes into the
picture because only in
application.properties for value only
we have assigned the Kafka Avro
serializer. So only for value
serialization
this will get invoked and this is
actually own flow.
Get the schema and this whole flow
again.
So this, let's put into
a backlog now.
The compatibility check which I will
cover soon.
Okay?
Now,
consumer read the event.
So,
Kafka now has event present.
Okay? Kafka now has event present like
it has magic
magic number,
is schema ID,
and the payload. Like this it has
record.
Now consumer says that, "Hey, give me
the data."
And now Kafka return the bytes. Now what
would happen consumer side? So, consumer
side deserializer, Kafka Avro
deserializer. Now, let again consumer we
have key and value.
Key I'm using a string deserializer.
Only for value I'm using Kafka Avro
deserializer. So, only for value
it will goes to the Avro deserializer.
Now, this is the flow for the Avro
deserializer.
What it will do? Whatever
Okay?
Whatever the object it is getting.
Oh, not object, whatever the byte it is
getting.
It has this, right? Magic, a schema ID,
payload.
It first check, okay, magic bit, let's
say it has zero. So, it knows that
next four byte is a schema and after
that payload.
So, it has no it knows that how to read
the rest of the payload. Okay? I told
you currently for this Avro
you can say that
the Confluent Schema Registry currently
has zero only.
Now,
the next it will read is that read the
schema ID.
Okay? So, first it will check its cache.
It will check its cache that, "Hey, for
this is schema ID, let's say 1001,
do we have the schema present in the
cache or not?" So, currently let's say
this is the first time.
So, a schema is not present into the
cache.
So, no.
So, what it will do is
invoke the schema registry. It will make
a HTTP call and it will say that, "Hey,
this is the schema ID.
Give me the schema."
It return the schema. I told you, right?
In the payload only values are present.
C1 5 55.0.
So,
what are the field?
So, see, consumer might have also have
an order.
It but it can't use its its own version.
It need to know
that
what is present into for this a schema
ID
the schema ID which I'm getting
the exact schema schema which is present
into the schema registry. It can rely on
to that only for reading this payload.
Okay? So, that's why for this a schema
ID since it doesn't have in to the
cache, it called the schema registry. It
get the data.
Now, first it will put that, "Okay, this
is the schema ID.
This is the schema. Put into the cache."
So, the next time it doesn't have to
make the call.
Okay? So, now this is has a schema
present from the registry. And if it is
already present into the cache, then
again come directly come to it. No need
to hit the schema registry.
Now, you have the schema which is from
coming from the registry.
Okay?
Now, let's say this is from the
registry. The schema
from registry.
Now, what it will do? It will read the
payload. So, first is order ID string.
This deserializer know that, "Okay, this
many bytes make a string.
So, this is order ID. Second is customer
ID which is also string. So, it knows
that, "Okay, this many bytes make a
string.
So, this is customer ID.
Third, quantity int. So, it knows that
how many bytes it has to read.
It is
quantity. Next is total amount which is
double.
So, it read that many bytes
and assign to total amount.
So, using the schema from registry
it use the order proper order
and
knows the value for each field.
So, at this point of time, it return a
generic record.
Generic record means that uh you can
access like record
\dot} get
order ID, record \dot} get customer ID,
record \dot} get quantity, total amount,
like this you will get.
And you will get the value.
Okay?
But
sometime what you have to do is like
instead of working with generic record,
you have to work with proper order
itself, order object itself.
Okay?
So
you can make it uh so you we can also
convert this generic record to order
object simply. So first thing is we have
to enable this into application \dot}
properties.
Reader equals to true, specific Avro
reader equals to true.
What this will do?
So it will check in consumer
it will check, hey do you have
\dot} avsc
file?
Okay?
It will read that.
Okay? And now what it will do
first in the schema registry
it will check
the name is order, the schema registry
which is coming, right? In the schema
registry
it also have like what is the name
and what is the name space.
So
it will check that the name is order,
name space is com.edea.schema.
So what it will when you have set this
property true
what it will do is that this
deserializer will look for order \dot}
java class within this name space of the
consumer.
If it present
it will convert this generic record to
this order class. If not, it will simply
return this generic record itself.
Okay?
So very simple. So now here if you see
that in consumer
in consumer
in Avro
I have also put order.avsc. This is
required just because
I want I don't want to work with generic
record.
In industry in production generally
we work with an object itself not with
like generic record like I do
record.getOrderID.
Okay? Because there is no you can say
that type validation. I need to do two
string and all.
With order it would be like simple
getter and setter I can use it.
So since we are using Avro deserializer
that's why you can't create your own
like order.java something. You have to
create like here I have created dot
avsc.
Whatever you have to maintain. This is
consumer specific snapshot you can say.
Generally it is better if you use the
same. Okay? But here let's say I'm using
a record order schema is this. Whatever
the field which I have to add I kept
here.
And for consumer also this is my
consumer.
Do Maven clean
compile.
What it will do is it will create this
order.java within this namespace target
Avro
and it will create com.eda.schema
com.eda.schema.order.java.
So now I have this order object present
here.
So now when you have this property set
to true
specific Avro reader equals to true
so
the schema which is coming from registry
from there it will check okay what is
the name? Order. Namespace is let's say
com
the same right? com.eda.schema.
So within this is key within this name
is space it will check for order. If
consumer has it,
it will do the mapping automatically.
Okay, that's what I have written here.
If found,
com.eda.
Let's say
whatever the schema.order.
If found, do the mapping. If not, return
generic record itself.
And in application.properties,
I will tell you my dependency same as
producer. You don't have to do anything.
I told you that when you add a
serializer dependency, it will also
bring deserializer.
If you
want to convert
this generic record to order,
okay, then you can add a schema because
you need a parser for AVSC.
And then you also have to add a plugin
so that it will generate a Java class
out of this
.AVSC.
Okay?
Now in application.properties, very
simple. Application name, consumer also
need to talk with Kafka. So, bootstrap
server, consumer group ID,
deserializer key deserializer I'm using
a string deserializer only.
Value deserializer only I am using Kafka
Avro deserializer. And for this value
itself,
this flow would be
followed.
Okay?
If you want for key also, again, you can
do that also.
No problem.
And it also has to talk with registry to
fetch if it is missing in the cache,
schema ID versus schema. So, it we have
to provide where it consumer can talk to
schema.
And
schema Avro reader true if you want
generic record to convert to a Java
object.
Okay? So, you have added a dependency.
You have added application.properties.
And this is the AVSC file I have added.
Name is order. Name space is this. So,
order.
java file would be created within this
name space.
And here,
this is the listener.
Topic, listen to this topic.
And here,
I am using this consumer record.
This is the order.
Okay? So, record.getValue,
I'm not getting generic record. No, I'm
getting direct order.
Because I have made this true.
And I have a order schema present.
This order
class present in the same schema name
space which
producer
which is present into the schema coming
from registry.
But if it not able to find in this
order,
it will be like a generic record here.
Got it?
So, we can do that also testing.
So, first thing is producer. Let me fix
it also again whatever we have changed.
So, this should be int.
Controller here,
change it back to int value.
Okay? And it publish to int again.
Let's do Maven
clean compile.
Done.
Let's start the producer again.
Cool. Now, let's come to the consumer.
Huh, the schema registry consumer.
.avsc, exact same name space
what I have for producer, right?
And same fields.
I have a listener.
Okay.
Uh the same listening to this this order
would be generated from
directly
from the AVSC.
And application.properties
schema registry you are URL Avro reader
equals to true. Only for value
deserializer I'm using Avro.
Key using a string.
Properties same.
Okay. So, I have a plugin the same
thing.
Now, let's do one
Maven clean compile first once
for safety.
Now, let's start the consumer.
Now, in producer let hit
103.
It's No. Okay, it should be integer,
right? Two.
Okay.
So, here
if you see consumer
able to read this order ID.
It worked.
Okay.
Order.get order ID it printed.
So, clear?
So, now
producer is not like change anything.
So, now let's come back
to this part. If you remember, we in the
producer I told that whenever producer
is trying to publish anything
it goes to the validation and if the
validation pass, then only it will
proceed further. Otherwise, it will
fail. Or you can say that whenever a new
or change in the schema
producer is doing
it will check if the new schema is
compatible with the old.
If yes,
it will record the new schema into
underscore schemas topic.
Else, it will throw an exception.
Now, question is
what's the logic behind this? How it
check
whether it is compatible or not, new
schema is compatible or not.
Now, let's jump into
compatibility level.
So, we have backward, forward, full,
backward transitive, forward transitive,
full transitive.
Very simple.
Many engineer get confused with this,
but let me tell you how I generally like
without revising it or something, I
always recall it.
Backward.
Consider that this is all this
compatibility check you can say that a
schema
registry is doing a compatibility check
to save consumer.
So, producer is changing the schema.
And when producer change it, consumer
should not break it.
So, understand with this one. Very
simple. Now, let's say
this schema registry purpose is to
protect the consumer.
So, understand with this. In Kafka, we
have a message.
Each message has a schema.
Like each message is associated with a
particular schema only, right?
Because in Kafka, you can say that we
have
you have a payload, which is nothing but
a message and schema ID. So, it belong
to a particular schema.
Right? Similarly,
consumer
read it.
And after that, it will uh
convert it to its order object. That's
it. So, this order object might be
another like it has its own
schema, right? So, it's reading it to
its own schema.
Okay? So, it has its own version.
So, what is the possibility? V1, V1, V2,
V2, V1, V2, V1, V2.
So, these are all the possible
combination.
So, here if you see, when both message,
the payload is in the let's say schema
version one.
And in the consumer also,
it has exactly the same field. Okay?
Then, it's the no issue. Okay, we don't
have to worry about this case.
Similarly, we don't have to worry about
this uh use case when both are in new
version. Okay, every message is V2,
every consumer is also in V2. We don't
have to worry about this.
Consider these two scenarios.
Consumer is on latest version.
Okay, latest version,
but message it is reading is the old.
Understand that again.
Consumer is using the new version.
Okay?
And new schema version, but if it read
the message which is on old schema,
what would happen? We need to test this.
We need to validate this.
Another use case is, what if consumer is
in
schema version one,
if it read a message which is written
with the schema version V2,
what would happen?
So, these two use cases we have to
validate mostly.
So, now here if you see, think from the
consumer perceptive.
Backward means we are looking back into
the system. And from consumer
perceptive, consumer is
let's say on version two.
Now it's looking back into the message
which are written with the old schema
version one.
So, that's backward.
Okay?
So, all the validation happen in this
like, okay, what if consumer uses this
version two schema and read a message
which is written with version one.
Backward.
Forward means your consumer is old.
Your consumer is on version one only,
schema version one.
But if we read a message
which is written with version two, it is
looking forward. Your schema your
consumer is old.
But it's looking forward, message
written with version two. That is
forward.
So all the validation runs from this
perspective.
Old schema on consumer, what if it read
the new
schema messages?
Understand with this example, it will
get more clear to you. So backward is
default.
Means consumer with new schema version,
consumer with new schema version can
read old schema event or not.
Example,
let's say in the schema registry is V1.
Version one. And in the version one we
have only name, order ID.
Type is int, only one.
Int order ID. Only one we have. This is
schema version one.
Now producer is sending event with new
schema. Producer has changed the schema
and it is making one send call with the
new schema.
Order ID,
int order ID, and also string status,
which has default pending. Now it is
sending this.
Now what is schema registry will do?
Schema registry will think, let's say we
are using backward compatibility level.
Schema registry will think from a
perspective that, okay,
what if this version two consumer
is on this version?
And it read a message that is
written with V1. What would happen?
So it has different rules like, okay,
let's say
we have added a new field here. Correct,
we have added a new field. So, it will
run a rule that okay,
this is the version one. Message is
written with version one.
And producer is sending this
where it has added a new field.
Okay, so this rule it will run.
And since we are using backward, it will
think from perceptive that consumer with
new schema
version two. Means consumer is on
version two. So, it's just thinking.
Okay.
Just putting consumer into one of the
shoes. Let's say consumer is on version
two.
Means consumer has order ID and consumer
has a status which is default pending.
Now, this consumer read a message which
is written on V1.
Okay, so let's say in Kafka there is a
message with just order ID. What would
happen?
So, this is safe. It will say that this
is safe rule say that because now let's
say when it read it,
what would happen?
It will get the order ID. This order ID
ultimately will get mapped to this.
And since this consumer is also
expecting a status, the status is not
there.
Since it has default, so it will use
default pending.
Okay. So, this is safe. It will allow
producer to go.
Okay.
No problem. You have defined a
pending.
So, with backward
scenario, it will use this perceptive
consumer putting consumer on the version
two.
And see that if it read the old message,
will it break or not? No.
Similarly, let's say if producer remove
Let's say earlier
in the V1,
it has only order ID.
And then added new field without
default. Now, let's say
producer has added a new field a status,
but there is no default.
The schema registry will not allow it.
Why? Because it will again use the same
thing. Because backward, right? Consumer
on the new schema V2
reading an old Kafka message order ID,
will it be able to properly complete the
read?
Order ID ultimately get mapped to order
ID.
It don't know how to fill a value for
the status and there is no default
value.
So, no. Not allowed. So, it will fail
it.
Okay? Now, let's say use case three.
Producer has removed the field.
In the earlier V1 registry, it has two
field.
int order ID, string status.
But now producer is sending an event
with only V2 with only order ID.
Will it allow it or not? So, what it
will do? It will again think from
perceptive that, okay, if my consumer is
on V2,
means only order ID present.
But in the Kafka, let's say old message
version one, it has order ID
and status. What would happen? Will
consumer will be able to read it
properly?
From message order ID would be properly
mapped.
Status, consumer doesn't have a status,
so this will be ignored.
Yeah, no problem. Everything will fine.
Nothing will break. Our application will
not crash.
So, like this
it will check.
Okay? So, if you have added a new field,
so in schema whatever it will find,
okay, it added a new field,
remove a new field,
or change the type. So, all those rule
will run.
Putting
consumer in one of the perceptive. In
backward, consumer
re- assume that it would have a
new schema reading the message with the
old schema and then think from that
perceptive.
Forward is like
consumer
is on
old schema, let's say V1,
reading the message which is written
with the new schema V2.
And from that perceptive it will think
very simple.
Again, the same let's say take the same
example
in the schema registry we have version
one which has only one field.
Now producer is changing the schema
schema
by doing certain news and
but it has to be validated. Now version
two has order ID and status.
So now it will do the validate. Okay,
new field is added.
So my consumer
is on version one. So it has only order
ID.
Now the message in Kafka let's say on
version two. It has order ID and status.
So this order ID will go properly map to
this.
A status consumer doesn't have the
field. No problem. It will ignore it. So
this is safe.
If new field is added
with the forward logic that is safe.
Remove field with the default.
Now let's say this is earlier schema in
which status has default pending.
Now producer has removed it. So this is
a new schema update you can say producer
is trying to do.
Will it be allowed or not? So again it
will check that okay let's put consumer
old. So it is on V1. So it has order ID
and status
pending.
Okay, now it is reading a message which
is old.
Which is no new.
Which is V2. Which has only order ID.
Order ID map to order.
It is expecting a status. Not present so
it will use default. So this is safe.
Okay.
So I can make it green.
Remove field without default. So if
default is not present then it should
not be allowed.
Got it? Backward forward, how
it put the consumer into one of the
shoes and then check whether crash will
happen or not.
Full means backward plus forward. So, it
will run all the rules like let's say
whatever the schema producer is sending.
If in this producer if in this is schema
it has added a field, deleted a field,
also change the type. So, it will check
all from the perspective from backward
and then from forward both.
Then we have backward transitive,
forward transitive, full transitive.
Means let's say we can have many
version.
And now producer is trying to send a new
version let's say new schema version
which ultimately become V4.
So, with this backward forward and all
it will always check the new schema with
the last one.
But with transitivity
with transitive
this new schema which producer is trying
to send, it will check with not only
last with also all previous version.
That's the only difference.
It do not just compare with last version
but all previous version.
Got it?
Now it is clear?
Like how it determine? So, now if I come
to that point
where it throws an exception, where it
was.
It throws an exception at there.
Now can you know
how
it determine whether this should throw
an exception or not?
Where it gone?
So,
what we have done is we have changed
from integer to string.
Integer to string. And we are running a
backward.
So, in the backward it will put
consumer.
Consumer into new.
Correct? So, into the new it will say
that okay quantity it expect as a
string."
It looking backward. Message returned
with the old one.
Old one one was int quantity.
So, this quantity, this is a string,
will it be able to map it? No.
It will throw an exception.
Incompatible type that it says that.
Okay?
Do not match with the old schema.
String not compatible with the writer
type int.
Got it?
This is how it does the validation.
Now, you might be thinking how we can
set this configuration level. So, very
simple. In a schema registry.properties,
if you remember where we set the
where when we set up a schema registry,
we have set up, right? There we can add
compatibility.level equals to forward,
backward, full, whatever you want.
But, you can say that this will get
applies to all.
Like all subjects.
Order-events
value, order-event key. If you have
different topic itself, payment-event
value, payment-event key. To all topics,
different topics
this will get applied. So, it's a
global.
So, once you do this, you can override
it to a specific subject itself.
So, you can hit the rest API \slash}
config \slash} subject.
Whatever the specific subject,
topic-whether value or key.
Compatibility, whichever you want. So,
you can make a put request also. So, it
will just override for this subject.
Clear?
So, I know this is a very big topic, and
I tried to cover it in a single video.
But, I tried to cover it everything.
Try it out. I will also push the code
into the Git, so you can also practice.
But, this is very interesting topic. Do
practice with your hand. Things will get
clear.
Okay, guys. Thank you. Bye.